We talked about four different data types yesterday, four different container data types.
We talked about lists, two bowls, sets, dictionaries.
Do you think that these other container types have comprehensions?
Yeah. So if I wanted to do a set comprehension,
I would use, I remember that set is kind of those curly braces, right?
This is a dictionary. We remember that.
But as long as there are items in it, then it's a set.
We're going to use this curly brace syntax.
Let's say we want to do a set of our squares.
I would do the same thing that I did in my list comprehension.
I would say four num in range.
Let's give it a bigger range now for num in range 11.
That's my loop.
And then my action is just num times num.
Remember sets are unordered.
So you won't see the results in order like you would in the list.
And to quickly check that, I can change the start and the end.
And confirm my assumptions.
What's the difference in syntax between a set and a dictionary?
Can you consider a set to be, you know, a collection of keys?
Just keys. What's different about a dictionary?
That's a value of the test of those keys.
Yes. Key value pairs.
What's different between our syntax for a set and our syntax for a dictionary?
And that commas, because you differentiate the items in your set by commas.
But it is cool and yeah.
So what if I wanted to make a dictionary where the key was the original number and the value was the square?
So my key is the original number.
The value is the square.
So we know I have to put in a colon.
Where does the key go before the value are?
Right, before the value.
Now I turned my set comprehension into a dictionary comprehension.
Just like, I showed you F strings before.
You can use F strings in your comprehensions.
So let's say I had my list of names right here.
I can do a list or set comprehension.
I can do a dictionary comprehension.
But just for simplicity, I'm going to do a list comprehension.
And I'm going to say four names in names.
And as my expression, I can put an F string.
And say the name is name.
Let's say I had a list of names with dups in it.
I'm going to call it dups names.
And there's going to be nine here and max.
And you know, you know, again.
I know that I can call set on dups names.
And I will take out the duplicates.
I can also call set on a list comprehension.
Let's say that I wanted to get the length of each name in this list.
So I would say four names in dups names.
And I would print out the, I would, sorry.
The value would be the length of the name.
And so my set just has three in for it.
Because the name Nina has the length of the same length twice.